

COMAN VALI

Technical Manager - CMN IT SERVICES

Age 39 from Bucuresti, married

Contact details

Email: valicoman@yahoo.com Tel: 0722514112

Address: Street David Ilie 26,Sector 4,Bucharest,Romania

About me

Responsible for the day to day IT requirements of the company such as user management, trouble shooting, help and advise.

Maintaining desktop applications, local area networks, IT security and telecommunications.

Cyber security specialist with experience in cloud computing and private corporate security systems.

Knowledge of current best practices, including best practices for application programmable interfaces

Extensive experience evaluating and discerning malignant traffic patterns that could signal an imminent data breach

Proficient written and verbal communication skills

Knowledge of network protocols and common programming languages used in interactive online environments

Detail-oriented approach to process analysis designed to reveal contributing causes to complex systems.

Professional experience

Experience by departments

IT Hardware: 21 years and 4 months

Sep 2015 - present

Technical Manager - CMN IT SERVICES

4 years

Bucharest | IT Hardware | IT / Telecom

CMN IT SERVICES, Blvd. Alexandru Obregia 2a, Bucuresti, Romania

Acquired skills and knowledge:

Adobe Premiere Pro, salesman, think strategically, Take an organisation-wide perspective, Understand the external environment, Judge when to intervene, Hold managers accountable, In-depth knowledge of different models of cell phones both old and new , Cell phone repair technician, Manager/cell phone repair technician, Excellent hand-eye coordination and ability to perform repairs, Proffesional demeanor with customers and coworkers, Exceptional knowledge of cellphone operating systems and features, Capably of working independently or with a team, Proven loyalty to a specific position and company, Windows all kind, Linux all kind, MacOS all kind, Ubuntu all kind, Android all kind

Nov 2001 - Sep 2015

Technical Manager - Xcom Computers

13 years and 11 months

Bucharest | IT Hardware | IT / Telecom

XCOM ,str. NITU VASILE NR 1,Bucuresti,Romania

Acquired skills and knowledge:

TCP/IP, HTML, Linux, SQL, Macos, Windows 7, Ubuntu, WLan, Windows Server, Windows 8, WAN, Network Administration, cisco routers, Firewalls, netapp, network architecture, Windows 10, cyber security, network development, Managing a team of over 30 admi nistrative & technical staff. Strengthening the IT infrastructure through to implementing new technologies. Responsible for hardware and software installation, Cisco Wirelles

Jul 1997 - Jan 2001

Manager sell ,technical manager - Pro Line Computers

3 years and 7 months

Bucharest | IT Hardware | IT / Telecom

Manager Vanzari si tehnic

Proline Computers, Blvd. Dimitrie Cantemir, nr 20, Bucuresti, Romania

Acquired skills and knowledge:

Windows, Linux, Microsoft Office, Windows XP, Windows 7, Windows Server, Windows 8, Adobe Premiere Pro, CyberLink PowerDirector, Photoshop, system utilities, Windows 10, Microsoft Windows, OpenOffice

Education

2001 - 2006 Bachelor's degree - SPIRU HARET UNIVERSITY

EUROPEAN RELATIONS | BUCHAREST

Study certificate, unlicensed, situation university years

1996 - 2001 High School / Vocational school - TECHNICAL COLLEGE DUMITRU MOTOC

INDUSTRIAL | BUCHAREST

TECHNICAL COLLEGE Dumitru Motoc, Bucuresti, Romania

1987 - 1995 Elementary school - Scoala 99

Scoala Generala | Bucuresti

Skills

General skills

Strengthening the IT infrastructure through to implementing new technologies., Having strong IT, Microsoft Windows XP, Microsoft Office, Re sponsible for the day to day IT requirements of the company such as user management, Take an organisation-wide perspective, Understand the external environment, Judge when to intervene, Extensive knowledge of: Microsoft Windows Server 2000, Windows 10, Windows 8, Build and maintained positive relationships with customers, Installed and routinely upgraded software and hardware for end-users, Analyzed and tested applications and system software for user compatibility, Set up audio-visual equipment for PTA and USD board meetings, Provided technical suport for smartphones and hand-held devices, Human resurces manager, Organizational skills, Problem solving, Customer service, Understanding clients, Interpersonal skills, Communication, Time management, Staff training development, Executive team leadership, Helpdesk, Data analiyst, Database administrator, decision making, industry knowledge, it manager, IT Support Technician, network engineer, system administrator, understanding bussines needs

Skills from work experience

Windows, Linux, Microsoft Office, Windows XP, Windows 7, Windows Server, Windows 8, Adobe Premiere Pro, CyberLink PowerDirector, Photoshop, system utilities, Windows 10, Microsoft Windows, OpenOffice, TCP/IP, HTML, SQL, Macos, Ubuntu, WLan, WAN, Network Administration, cisco routers, Firewalls, netapp, network architecture, cyber security, network development, Managing a team of over 30 admi nistrative & technical staff. Strengthening the IT infrastructure through to implementing new technologies. Responsible for hardware and software installation, Cisco Wirelles, salesman, think strategically, Take an organisation-wide perspective, Understand the external environment, Judge when to intervene, Hold managers accountable, In-depth knowledge of different models of cell phones both old and new , Cell phone repair technician, Manager/cell phone repair technician, Excellent hand-eye coordination and ability to perform repairs, Proffesional demeanor with customers and coworkers, Exceptional knowledge of cellphone operating systems and features, Capably of working independently or with a team, Proven loyalty to a specific position and company, Windows all kind, Linux all kind, MacOS all kind, Ubuntu all kind, Android all kind

Foreign languages

Romanian - Advanced, English - Advanced

Other info

Qualifications

I have over 24 years of experience in Networking, and I love working in a strong and friendly environment. During the years I have gathered knowledge about Network development, operations and maintenance; Routers, Switches, Firewalls and Load balancers. Good knowledge for main operating systems: Windows server, Linux, Mac OS and Ubuntu, Windows 7,8,10 - 32 or 64bit

Cisco certified security

Cisco Wireless

Cisco routers

NetApp

SQL and database management

Switches and Routers

Over 24 years of experience in Network Administration and Architecture

WAN, WLAN, TCP/IP

Can handle HTML, CSS and SQL

Firewalls setup and operation

Troubleshooting for cables, i can make all kind of cables and i work a lot with cable cat 5 and cat 6 and i know to work with tester cables.

I can set up and install all the kind of operating systems and a lot of settings for all. In my shop i am network admin, manager, technical manager, i do all the stuff. For the moment i think i am ready for everything in this area.

acquired on Mar 2019

Volunteering

RECYCLE WORLD

period Feb 2012 - Feb 2012

"Let's Do It Romania"

Skills

period Jan 1997 - May 2018

Great sense of customer service

Good listening and communication skills

Good organizational skills

Ability to make decisions quickly

Ability to work effectively in a fast paced changing environment

Great team spirit

I own an it bussines in Bucharest Romania for 17 years,I sell computers,Iaptops and phones or parts of them and i also provide service for all.I'm looking for a new opportunities for me and I am searching for a long time relation with a company.If you are interested to hire in your company a good worker with a lot of experience please feel free to contact me.I am interested to work in a big company and if you want to develop your bussines I am the perfect person.

Trainings

I worked 4 years in Romanian Parliament, practical study, 4 hours per day. Here i learned a lot of stuff about computers and networking.

period Jan 1997 - May 2000

Good understanding of IT infrastructure and application systems

Experience in manufacturing environment

Familiarity with automotive industry an advantage

Good communication skills with ability to communicate in English

Self-motivated with ability to take action proactively

Team player with ability to collaborate with fellow team members locally and overseas

Strong personality to always insist on doing things the right way

Certifications

Certifications

period Jan 1997 - May 2018

24+ years' experience in senior IT / system administrator positions in an online / web-based product company

Proven experience in managing high availability production environments with an experience in designing and implementing cost-effective IT solutions

In-depth knowledge of Apache and Tomcat web servers, LINUX and Microsoft

Strong network related skills - Firewalls, routers, switching

A solid understanding of storage and backup concepts and technologies

Good understanding of application and IT security

Good experience with the ISstandard

High availability during non-standard working hours to support unexpected production incidents

Excellent interpersonal skills

Hands on, hardworking, team player

Hobbies

I've had over 30 personal cars, I am a family man convinced, I am a good cook, I go to the basketball tournaments, Playing basketball with my kids, My hobby is to travel with my family, I play tennis, I read books and play with the family dog Max, I like to ride my bike

Driving license

Category B

acquired on 18 Aug 1999